

Soumik Nath

Irumbuliyur Tambaram Chennai E-mail: soumik.nath822@gmail.com

Phone: 9748621059

SUMMARY

A passionate and enthusiastic professional involved in end to end development of agile applications. A team player with ability to adapt to new technologies quickly and implement them to provide first time right on time product delivery. Has developed a good experience of communicating with clients and understand product requirements. Has the ability to perform well under pressure to meet the deadlines. To give the best to the serving organization through dedicated work, positive attitude and mutual coordination.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Core Java 8
- Advanced Java Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring Batch, Microservices with Spring Boot, Apache Kafka
- Mapper Languages- iBatis, Hibernate, Spring-Data-JPA, Spring-Data-MongoDb, GraphQL query language
- Frontend Angular 8, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap
- Docker

TOOLS

- Dependency, configuration Maven
- Servers JBoss, Tomcat
- Security checks, Project build & Deployment Sonar, Checkmarkx, Jenkins, Udeploy, Microsoft TFS
- IDE platforms Eclipse, STS, Intellij, Microsoft VS Code
- Project Synchronization Git, SVN
- Database MySql, Oracle, SqlServer, GraphQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Barclays

May 2022 — Present

Senior FSE - Payment Merchant Services

Payment Restful Service (PRS) -

It is a Spring Boot application which acts as a wrapper over the existing Core Payment services and is exposed as payment service API(s) to be consumed by merchants for payment transactions belonging to different categories.

Roles & Responsibilities -

- Enhancements for existing spring security module in the application
- Enhance/Add new API(s) end-to-end to be consumed by merchants for payment transactions
- Update existing logging implementation of the entire application
- Junit/Integration tests code coverage
- Build/Deployment of the application

PayPageST -

It is a custom payment page UI based application used by merchants to allow their customers to provide payment details to complete orders purchased from ecommerce websites.

Roles & Responsibilities -

- Enhancements of the application including merchant specific payment page customizations, configurational changes for payment transactions
- Bug fixes for existing backend modules and UI
- Updating / Fixing/ Adding Junits & E2E integration tests for code coverage.
- Updating /Adding coverage in automation test suite for successful execution of accessibility test cases.
- Build and Deployment
- OWASP and Veracode related vulnerability fixes

CDCT (Card-data-conversion-tool) -

It is used for encrypting list of card details taken from different customers for further processing of settlement of payment transactions by another Barclays tool.

Roles & Responsibilities -

- Involved in cryptographic related changes which includes fingerprint update of existing certificates, replacement of old with new chained certificates
- OWASP vulnerability fixes
- Veracode vulnerability fixes
- Configuration changes related to encryption/decryption of the input file
- Build/Deployment/Release of the application

Optum(UnitedHealthGroup)

March 2021 — May 2022

Senior Software Engineer

Project: ICP - Individual Care Plan

ICP is an internal product used by the doctors and nurses of United Health Care(UHC) group of medical hospitals diagnosis and treatments of patients seeking service from their medical centers.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Full-Stack Developer

- Develop end to end modules for the application(frontend & backend) with Spring Boot and Angular 8
- Perform simple queries to extract/update/insert patient data into GraphQL database tables via graphql rest APIs
- Manage and update regular tasks in Rally
- Configuring projects with Maven
- Running security and vulnerability scans with Sonar and Checkmarkx
- Perform unit testing of the modules by developing respective junit test cases
- Synchronizing, committing projects with tools like Git
- Implement microservice communication between micro products via Rest and Apache Kafka streams
- Configure products for Azure deployments via Jenkins build/deploy pipelines created by DevOps

Senior Consultant - 1

Project: Lumada Data Catalog

Lumada Data Catalog is a product which uses AI and machine learning capabilities to analyze historical data of a company for successful data governance and compliance

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Back-End Developer

- Understanding the existing flow and suggest improvements where ever feasible
- Fix bugs in the existing product to improve performance and remove glitches as per customer feedback

Deloitte

August 2020 — Dec 2020

Technology Analyst

Project: ECB Mortgage

ING is an Australian bank which works on different initiatives including personal loan applications, different kind of credit card offerings, account openings, etc. The project focuses on assessing a customer applying for a Mortgage loan to determine the probability for the customer to fall into a defaulter list for not repaying the loan.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Back-End Developer

- Understanding the existing microservice architecture for risk assessment and add new micro-services to risk assessment ecosystem using Spring Boot and it's associated technologies to facilitate calculation of risk scores which determines probability for defaulter.
- Write Junits to ensure complete code coverage of the newly built microservices.
- Adding security on the newly created microservices to adhere to the standard security implementation followed for ING open banking applications.
- Work with DevOps and create Build/Release pipelines and setup OpenShift containers to facilitate microservice deployment.

Deloitte

Oct 2019 — July 2020

Technology Analyst

Project: ING SRE (Site Reliability Engineering)

ING is an Australian bank which works on different initiatives including personal loan applications, different kind of credit card offerings, account openings, etc. The project focuses on migrating the existing banking services of ING which is monolithic in nature into micro service architecture.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Back-End Developer

- Analyze the existing web services and gather knowledge which involves different database transactions happening in and around the services, understand exception handling, security design of the endpoints and contract response the service endpoints receive to process the request
- Implementing the services using Spring Boot framework in order to fit micro service architecture
- Implement the dao layer using spring-data-jpa repositories to handle the financial transactions required to process customer requests
- Participate in agile scrum meetings and associated ceremonies to understand business requirements and ensure delivery with proper agile methodologies

Deloitte

Technology Analyst

Project: AlSummitChallenge

This project is a part of Deloitte firm initiatives which is a competition event organized by Deloitte every year as part of applying solution with AI in real time use cases. It involved developing the event application which will be used for Deloitte employees to participate in the event.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Back-end Developer

- Develop backend services to handle participants registration, login with security, score calculation logic based on points gained from team activities in the competition
- Work with UI dev team to help in integrating backend services with the frontend UI

Deloitte

Aug 2019 — March 2020

Technology Analyst

Project: TFSJiraUtility

This project is a part of Deloitte firm initiatives which focus on creating different tools which can be utilized and reused by Deloitte or its clients for making projects more seamless and efficient. It automates the process of creating user stories for different project management tools like Jira, TFS, Rally, etc.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Full - Stack Developer

- Develop restful service endpoints using Spring Boot which will process the flow of creating user stories and also assign tasks to the stories created for different project management tools
- Design UI using Angular 8 with CSS and Html for the user to interact with the automation tool

Deloitte

May 2019 — Oct 2019

Technology Analyst

Project: ING Banking - Banking application

ING is an Australian bank which works on different initiatives including personal loan applications, different kind of credit card offerings, account openings, etc. The project mainly focuses on an initiative termed as debt consolidation which offers customers to consolidate all outstanding loans with a single loan amount from ING.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Back-End Developer

- Develop and maintain backend services which corresponds to different modules of the application with Spring Boot and microservices architecture
- Participate in agile scrum meetings and associated ceremonies to understand business requirements and ensure delivery with proper agile methodologies
- Maintain code quality with different unit testing methodologies including Junits with Mockito, API testing, executing JMX tests on the developed services

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd.

September 2017 — May 2019

Associate Consultant

Project: MyBank - Account maintenance application

MyBank is one of the functioning components of the MySuite Treasury Application which is being used for GE internal business. The application provides a full-fledged user interface to an user which provides features starting from initiating a new account request for business till maintaining the account.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Full-Stack Developer

- Develop end to end modules for the application(frontend & backend) in ide platform including STS
- Perform simple queries for transactions of records with SqlDeveloper
- Manage and update regular tasks on Rally
- Configuring projects with Maven tool
- Running security and vulnerability scans with Sonar and Checkmarkx
- Perform unit testing of the modules by developing respective junit test cases
- Synchronizing, committing projects with tools like SVN
- Create backend endpoints with Restful web services

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd.

November 2016 — August 2017

Senior Analyst

Project: MyPayments - Capital Funding application

MyPayments is one of the functioning components of the MySuite Treasury Application which is being used for monitoring funds transfer for different GE business accounts. It comprises of features which allow users to create a payment request, decide payer, payee of the payment, preparing and releasing the payments to fund various ongoing businesses inside GE company.

Roles & Responsibilities -

Role - Full-Stack Developer

- Develop end to end modules for the application(frontend & backend) in ide platform including STS, Eclipse, etc.
- Perform simple queries for transactions of records with SqlDeveloper
- Manage and update regular tasks of Rally
- Configuring projects with Maven tool
- Running security and vulnerability scans with Sonar and Checkmarkx
- Perform unit testing of the modules by developing respective junit test cases
- Synchronizing, committing projects with tools like Git
- Create backend endpoints with Restful web services

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received 1 'Bravo' and 2 'Performer of the Quarter' recognitions (Optum)
- Selected as 'Star Performer of the month(Jun July 2020)' (Deloitte)
- Nominated twice as 'Star Performer of the Sprint' 2019 (Deloitte)
- Recognized with 'Spot Award' for outstanding contribution to the project within a short span of time and under critical circumstances - 2019 (Deloitte)
- Received 'Pat on the Back' from Project Manager for adapting to new project environment very quickly and performing well to meet client expectations - 2018 (Capgemini)
- Received client appreciation for adding cutomer value in project for making the overall execution time of the application faster - 2018 (Capgemini)
- Received client appreciation for delivering first time right and on time product 2017 (Capgemini)

EDUCATION

B-Tech 2012 — 2016

Academy Of Technology

Higher Secondary 2010 — 2012

Patha Bhavan

Secondary 2009 — 2010

La Maternelle High School

INTERESTS

Learning new technologies

- Photography
- Singing
- Virtual Gaming

REFERENCES

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/soumik-nath-3b6b71108/